字幕来源：奇遇电影字幕组
字幕特效：101eagle
压制：101eagle
上传UP：101eagle
露丝?
Ruth?
我妻子在哪
Where's my wife?
古特曼先生 你可不能这样偷偷在背后吓我一跳
Mr. Guttman!You can't be sneaking up on me like that!
我太太呢 露丝在哪里
Where is my wife?Where is Ruth?
很抱歉 古特曼先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Guttman,
你太太大约一周前过世了
your wife passed away about a week ago.
噢
Ah.
抱歉 请问你是?
I'm sorry. Who are you?
我叫保拉
My name's Paula.
曾是古特曼太太的护理
I was Mrs. Guttman's nursing aide.
你们家请我再多待一两周
Your family asked me to stay on for another week or two.
去吃点早餐吧
Let's get some breakfast.
吃完早餐你会感觉好些的
You'll be feeling better after breakfast.
你的鞋在哪
Where are your shoes?
等等 我去给你拿拖鞋
Hold on, let me get you some slippers.Tell you what.
用你的帽子去换双拖鞋 可以吗
Trade your hat for some slippers, okay?
好了 进来吧
All right. Now come in.
- 早安 泽夫 - 早安
Good morning, Zev.  Good morning.
但愿你没有很饿 早餐和往常一样少得可怜
I hope you're not too hungry.Breakfast is crummy as usual.
没关系 我不是很饿
That's okay.I'm not too hungry.
她是塞莱 你太太以前的朋友
That's Cele. She was friends with your wife.
我知道她是谁 我知道
I know who she is.I know who she is.
能给我们私聊的时间吗
Could you give us a minute, please?
噢 没问题
Oh, no problem...
他是马克斯
Max.
你没必要告诉我所有人的名字
You don't have to tell me everyone's name.
今晚是为露丝服丧的最后一晚对吗
Tonight is the last night sitting shiva for Ruth, yes?
你还记不记得你说过露丝死后
Do you remember what you said you would do
你要做什么
when Ruth died?
不记得了
No.
没事 没事
It's okay. It's okay.
我
I...
记下了所有事
wrote everything down
所以你
so you...
会记起来的
could remember.
跟我来 劳森鲍姆先生
Come on, Mr. Rosenbaum.
亲爱的
Darling.
你知道这张照片什么时候照的吗
Do you know when this picture was taken?
他们结婚的时候照的
It's from their wedding day.
1946年
1946.
你是在德国遇见奶奶的吗
Did you meet nanny in Germany?
噢 不 不是
Uh, no, no.
我在美国遇见她的
I met her in America.I met her...
在康尼
Coney...
- 在康尼岛 - 对
Coney Island.  Yeah.
嘿 为什么不拿给你哥哥看看呢
Why don't you show this to your brother, eh?
亚当 快看这个
Adam, look at this!
给 把这个放口袋里
Here. Put this away in your pocket.
现在
Now,
站起来
stand up.
告诉所有人你累了
Tell everyone you're tired,
然后独自一人看完
and go read it alone.
独自一人
Alone.
你累了
You're tired.
对 对
Yeah, yeah.
就这样 好的
Yeah. Good.
原谅我 我
Forgive me, I...
我有点累 我想我该去睡觉了
I'm a little tired,I think I should go to bed.
好的 爸爸
Yeah. Okay, Dad.
真是漫长的一周
It's been a long week.
是啊
Yeah.
- 佩恩车站 对吗 - 是的
Penn Station, right?  Yeah.
最后通知
Last call!
49号湖滨列车要发车了
49 Lake Shore Limited!
最后通知
Last call!
最后通知 要开车了
Last call,49 Lake Shore Limited!
那是你妈妈吗
Is that your mother?
是的
Yeah.
她不和你一起吗
She's not coming with you?
不 我去找我爸爸
No. I'm going to see my dad.
噢
Oh.
所以你是一个人咯
So, you're traveling all alone?
不是一个人 我的兄弟们在那呢
I'm not alone.My brothers are right over there.
噢?
Oh?
噢 我看见了
Oh, I see.
你也是去克利夫兰吗
Are you going to Cleveland too?
是的
Yeah.
为什么不坐飞机呢 那样更快
Why don't you fly?It's faster.
我也不知道
I don't know.
这可不是个好理由
That's not a good reason.
你这个不知天高地厚的小孩
You're a real whipper snapper, aren't you?
那你为什么不坐飞机去克利夫兰呢
Why don't you fly to Cleveland?
三张飞机票太贵了
Three plane tickets is too expensive.
那是我爸妈说的
That's what my mom and dad said.
好吧 这是个好理由
Well, that is a good reason.
我不坐飞机是因为我朋友在他写给我的信里
I don't fly because my friend told me to take the train
告诉我要坐火车
in the letter he wrote to me.
我想这也是个好理由
I guess that's a good reason, too.
我叫泰勒
My name is Tyler.
很高兴认识你 泰勒
Nice to meet you, Tyler.
我叫泽夫
My name's Zev.
真是个奇怪的名字
That's a strange name.
在希伯来语里 它的意思是"狼"
In Hebrew, it means "Wolf."
真酷
Cool!
我为你计划了所有事项
I have planned everything for you.
你必须精准地执行这些步骤
You must follow these steps precisely.
每做完一项就划掉一项
Cross them off as you accomplish each task.
我们已经通知过警方 他们向社区发出了
We've notified the police and they've issued
银色警报并启动反911系统
a silver alert as well as a reverse 911
我们...我们这边会竭尽全力
to the community, our...our staff is doing all that we can.
- 确实难以接受... - 我只是不敢相信
It's upsetting.  I just can't believe
发生的这一切
this is happening.
我们感到万分的抱歉
I can't tell you how sorry we all are.
我们会密切留意每个人
We do our best to keep an eye on everybody,
但...我相信你能理解的
but... I'm sure you can understand.
我们能帮到什么吗
Is there anything we can do to help?
除了付钱让你们看丢人还有别的吗
Besides paying you to lose people?
你父亲有信用卡吗
Does your father have a credit card?
他一旦使用你可以让银行联系你
You can tell them to call you if he uses it.
听着
Listen.
你母亲的护工告诉我
Your mother's nursing aid told me that
你父亲最近特别糊涂
your dad's been very confused lately.
是的 他患有痴呆
Yeah, yeah.That's because he has dementia.
而这也是起初我母亲把父亲一起带到这来的原因
And that's why my mother brought them here in the first place.
我明白 但是
I understand that. However,
通常在配偶死亡后
it's very common after the death of a spouse
会出现更多认知障碍
for more signs of neurocognitive disorders to emerge.
你有没有注意到你父亲的情绪波动
Have you noticed that your father's been having mood swings?
而且他几乎不再弹钢琴了
And he rarely plays the piano anymore?
我察觉到了一些 查尔斯
I've noticed a few things, Charles.
我想那时我们
I guess we were...
在你母亲的事情上太操劳了以至于我没有理会这些
so busy with your mom that I just dismissed them.
安心吧 我们会让他在你知晓前平安回来的
Let me reassure you,we'll have him back here before you know it.
在这些情况下
In these situations,
人不会走太远
people never wander too far.
露丝?
Ruth?
亚当?
Adam?
你奶奶在哪
Where is your grandmother?
亚当?
Adam?
你奶奶呢
Where is your grandmother?
你在跟我说话吗 泽夫
Were you talking to me, Zev?
我问你奶奶在哪
I asked you where your grandmother is.
一个在纽约州 一个在俄亥俄州
One is in New York.One is in Ohio.
你妹妹呢
Where is your sister?
我没有妹妹
I don't have a sister.
别玩那玩意儿了
Stop playing with that thing.
回答我
Answer me.
你...还好吗 泽夫
Are... are you okay, Zev?
我们在哪
Where are we?
在火车上
We're on a train.
去哪
To where?
克利夫兰
Cleveland.
克利夫兰?
Cleveland?
你要去见一个朋友
You're going to see a friend.
什么朋友
What friend?
给你写了你口袋里那封信的朋友
The one who wrote you the letter in your pocket.
能把我的游戏机还给我了吗
Can I have my PSP back?
露丝死了
Ruth is dead.
泽夫
Zev,
我要去和我兄弟们坐一会
I'm going to sit with my brothers for a little bit.
- 你好 - 嗯?
Excuse me.  Yeah?
嗨 我... 我儿子在火车上时你和他挨着
Hi. Uh...My son there said that you were sitting
而你看起来有些糊涂了
next to him on the train and that you seemed a little confused.
噢 是的
Oh, yes, that.
- 我对此感到很抱歉 - 噢 不会不会
I'm sorry about that.  Oh, no, no, no.
你不需要道歉 我们...
There's no need to apologize. We...
- 只是想确认你没事 - 噢我没事的
just want to make sure you're okay.  Oh, yes, I'm okay.
谢谢你 我很好
Thank you. I'm okay.
额...你要去哪需要帮忙吗
Um... You need help getting somewhere?
不用 会有人来接我的
No, no.Someone will be meeting me here.
我朋友说他会举一个
My friend said that he had a...
写有我姓名的牌子
sign with my name on it.
好的 我们会帮你找
Okay. Well, we'll help you find him.
这些车刚到
The cars are just down here.
你是姓古特曼吗
Is your last name Guttman?
是的
Yeah.
你坐的车看起来很时髦
Looks like you're riding in style.
再见 泽夫
Bye, Zev.
再见 再见
Goodbye. Goodbye.
走吧 孩子们
Let's go, boys.
- 古特曼先生? - 是的
Mr. Guttman?  Yeah.
好的
Good.
- 下午好 - 下午好
Good evening.  Evening.
我怎样帮到你呢
How can I help you?
我朋友向我推荐了你的店
My friend recommended your shop to me.
好的 请转告你的朋友我们很感谢他的推荐
Well, tell your friend we appreciate the recommendation.
- 你想要拿哪种呢 - 噢...
What are you looking to pick up?  Oh...
小一点的
Something small.
当然有
Sure thing. Okay.
- 能给我看看你的驾驶证吗 - 好的
Can I see your driver's license?  Yeah.
这儿...
Yeah...
好的
Okay.
比奇伍德 很棒的小镇
Beachwood. Nice town.
是的 但...
Yes. But, um...
我们搬走了
We've moved.
我们搬去离我儿子更近的住处了
We live closer to my son.
你拿我的驾驶证干什么
What are you doing with my license?
我在把你的信息输入FBI的背景调查数据库
I'm entering your information into the FBI background check database.
噢
Oh.
他们在调查什么
What do they look for?
一大堆资料 看你是否为已被定罪的重刑犯
A bunch of stuff.Whether you're a convicted felon,
涉嫌暴力犯罪
if you've been involved in a crime of violence,
被军队惩戒免职
dishonorably discharged from the army,
是否智力健全 或者是否过去五年内
mentally competent.If you've got more than one DUI offense
不止一次酒驾 是否是个逃犯
in the last five years,if you're a fugitive,
- 或者最近被指控重罪 - 逃犯?
or currently charged with a felony.  Fugitive?
是的 比如你在逃脱法律的制裁
Yeah, like, if you're running from the law.
你觉得我看起来逃得动吗
Do I look like I can run?
好吧 给你看些小一点的手枪
Uh, okay. Let me show you some of our smaller handguns.
我们应有尽有 西格绍尔 M1911 格洛克（均为手枪型号）
We got everything.SIG Sauers, 1911s, Glocks,
单动枪 双动枪
single action, double action.
- 先生 你懂枪吗 - 额...
Sir, do you know much about guns?  Um...
- 不懂 怎么了 - 那没关系
No. Why?     It's all right.
我们这什么类型的都有
We get all types in here.
好吧 新手的话...
Uh, okay. Beginners...
通常是用点22口径的
usually go with a .22.
它很轻 易上手 后坐力很小
It's light. Easy to use.Very little recoil.
我觉得这就是我朋友建议的
I think that's what my friend suggested.
好吧 依我来看
Okay. In my opinion,
你买点22就相当于拥有了一把气枪
you might as well get yourself a BB gun if you get a .22.
嘿 我不是在强行推销 但多花500块
Look, I'm not trying to give you the hard sell, but $500 more,
你能拥有一把真正有制动能力的枪
you can get yourself a gun with real stopping power.
这个是格洛克17 9mm手枪
Now this is a 9mm Glock 17.
格洛克? 这是德国枪 对吗
Glock? It is German, no?
接近正确答案了 它产自奥地利
You're in the right neighborhood.Manufactured in Austria.
这是世界上最流行的执法手枪 不错吧
That's the most popular law enforcement pistol in the world. Okay?
它的后坐力非常小 所以应该不会伤到手
It's got very little recoil so probably won't hurt your hand
但它肯定会伤到入侵者
but it'll definitely hurt the intruder.
这个好用吗
Is it easy to use?
但愿
I hope!
是的 它很简易
Yeah, it's simple.
好吧 但是...
Yeah, but...
不知你介不介意 可不可以
Would you mind, could you...
帮我写个使用说明书
write down the instructions for me?
当然可以 我的意思是 我可以示范给你看怎么使用
Uh, sure. I mean,I can show you how to use it.
不了 那是很好 但拜托了 帮我写下来吧
No, that would be good.But please, write it down for me.
我有时候会健忘
Sometimes I forget things.
顾客至上 这没问题
Yeah, we all do, right?That's no problem.
好的 一切都妥当了
Okay, you're good to go.
我去拿支笔 然后
I'll grab a pen, and um...
帮你写下使用说明
write it all down for you.
- 古特曼先生吗 - 对 古特曼
Mr. Guttman?    Guttman. Yeah...
你怎么知道
How did you know?
你朋友早些时候打过电话说你快到了
Your friend called earlier and said you'd be arriving soon.
房间已经为你准备好了
Your room's all ready for you.
房间号是
We have you in...
125 就顺着走廊走
125. Just down the hall.
- 我该付多少钱 - 已经付过了
How much do I owe?  It's all taken care of,
包括附加费
including incidentals.
对了 应你朋友的要求 我们为你订了明天早上的出租车
Oh, and I booked your taxi for the morning,like your friend asked.
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 喂? - 喂
Hello?  Hello.
- 泽夫吗 - 是我
Zev?    Yeah.
我是马克斯
It's Max.
我指示了酒店一些事项
I gave the hotel some instructions.
- 你还好吗 - 是的我还好 马克斯
Are you okay?  Yes, yes, I'm okay, Max.
你拿到枪了吗
And you got the gun?
嗯 拿到了
Yeah, yeah.
很好 很好
Good. Good.
你知道该做什么的
You know what to do.
照顾好自己 知道吗
Just take care of yourself, yeah?
晚安好梦 马克斯
You have a good night, Max.
晚安 泽夫
Good night, Zev.
露丝?
Ruth?
你把灯打开好吗
Turn on the lights, please.
太黑了 我看不...
It's dark in here. I can't...
看不清楚
I can't see.
- 你好 - 嗨
Hello.        Hi.
请问鲁迪・库兰德在家吗
Is Rudy Kurlander home?
在家 他在楼下
Yeah. He is downstairs.
你是...
Are you...
鲁迪・库兰德?
Rudy Kurlander?
是
Yes.
我是鲁迪・库兰德
I'm Rudy Kurlander.
你是?
Who are you?
你可以...呃...
Can you, uh...
把电视关掉吗
turn off the television?
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
现在 请你...
Now, please...
站到窗户旁边
stand by the window.
你是谁
Who are you?
站到窗户旁边
Stand by the window.
如果你不告诉我你是谁还有你来这儿的原因
I am not going to do anything until you tell me
我什么都不会做
who you are and why you're here.
咱们还是别争了
Let us not argue.
站到窗边去
Just stand by the window.
现在又要做什么
Now what?
得亮堂些我才能看清你的脸
I need to see light on your face.
- 把头转过去 - 你是谁
Turn your head.        Who are you?
别吼
Don't yell.
拜托 不要吼
Please, don't yell.
按我说的做 抬起头来
Do as I say. Turn your head.
你是德国人吗
Are you German?
是的
Yeah.
- 你也是德国人? (德语) - 是
You are also German?        Ja.
你多少岁了
How old are you?
88 Eighty-eight.
你曾在德军服役吗
Were you in the German army?
你在军队里做什么
What did you do?
- 那都过去了 - 英语 请说英语
It is in the past.        English. Please, English.
- 我不喜欢说德语 - 那都是70年前了
I do not like to speak German.        It's seventy years ago.
我那时太年轻
I was very young-
回答我的问题
Answer the question.
你是犹太人?
Are you a Jew?
没错
Yeah.
- 你当时在奥斯维辛集中营吗 - 我不在
Were you at Auschwitz?        No!
我们都这个岁数了 还有必要撒谎吗
We are too old for lies.
在战争结束前
I didn't know about Auschwitz
我都不知道奥斯维辛集中营的事
until after the war.
我当时在北非
I was in North Africa.
和隆美尔元帅一起
With General Rommel.
- 你有证据吗 - 有
You have proof?        Yes.
就在那边
Over there.
当我成为美国公民的时候 移民局的官员问我
When I became a US citizen, the immigration officer asked me
是否曾和纳粹政府
if I had ever associated
有关联
with the Nazi government of Germany
或者是否曾在集中营工作
or worked at a concentration camp.
我的回答说
I told the officer what I'll tell you.
是的 我效忠于我的国家 我是一名军人
Yes, I served for my country. I was a soldier.
我为自己身为德国人而自豪 所有人都为自己的国家而自豪
I was a proud German and that's what the men did.
我仍然为我为国家作出的贡献感到自豪
I'm still proud of my service.
这是隆美尔元帅
That's Rommel.
至于犹太人
As far as the Jews...
我并不关心犹太人 我认为希特勒是对的
I didn't care about the Jews. I thought Hitler was right.
犹太人给我们国家带来了太多麻烦
They caused many problems for the country.
我认为我们是在驱逐他们 或是把他们安置在劳动营里...
I thought we were deporting them or putting them in work camps...
而不是像他们所做的那样
Not what they did.
那太可耻了
It was shameful,
但我没有做那些事
but that was not me.
- 喂? - 是马克斯吗
Hello?        Is this Max?
是我
Yes.
我是泽夫
This is Zev.
呃... 不是...
Uh... It was...
不是他
not him.
- 你确定吗 - 我确定
Are you sure?        Yeah, I'm sure.
那你必须要继续
Then you must go on.
必须履行
You must do
你曾经承诺过的
what you said you would.
近些年来一直有传闻
There have been rumors for years
一些奥斯维辛集中营里的党卫队军官
that a number of Auschwitz SS officers
在战争接近尾声的时候
stole the identities of executed prisoners
冒名顶替了被处死的犹太人的身份
near the end of the war.
在我中风后不久
Shortly after my stroke,
有证据表明 一名奥斯维辛集中营军官
evidence was found that an Auschwitz Blockfuhrer
于19世纪40年代从德国移民
emigrated from Germany in the 1940s
并且最可能用假名鲁迪・库兰德
and was most likely living under the name
继续生活
Rudy Kurlander.
西蒙・维森塔尔中心(西蒙・维森塔尔中心是一个国际犹太人权组织 这组织是为了纪念纳粹在二次世界大战中被杀的犹太人而成立的)
The Simon Wiesenthal Center
找到了四名在那个时期移民至此的
has found four Rudy Kurlanders
鲁迪・库兰德
who emigrated during that period.
然而 没有足够的证据
However, there is not enough proof
逮捕他们其中任何一人
to arrest any of them.
他的真名是奥托・瓦利施
His real name is Otto Wallisch.
你必须要找到他
You must find him.
我正在寻找我父亲 他已经将近90岁了
I'm looking for my father. He's almost 90 years old.
他的名字叫泽夫
His name is Zev.
我在寻找我的父亲
I'm looking for my father.
他90岁了
He's 90 years old.
他几天前外出闲逛
He went wandering a few days ago.
他的名字是泽夫・古特曼
His name is Zev Guttman.
我不知道他是否随身携带了可以证明身份的证件
I don't know if he has any identification on him,
我甚至不确定他是否还记得自己的姓名
or... I don't even know if he remembers his name.
我想知道有没有人被送进医院
I've been wondering if anybody has been brought into the hospital.
你觉得我还没报警吗
Do you not think I've already called the police?
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我们快到加拿大边境了
we're approaching the Canadian border,
到时候大家都需要下车接受检查
at which point, we're all gonna have to get off the bus for inspection.
如果您能提前准备好您的护照或其他旅行证件
If you can have your passports and any travel documents ready,
将节省不少时间 谢谢合作
it'll make the process a lot faster. Thank you.
请出示申报单
Declaration card?
您此行的目的是?
Purpose of your trip?
拜访一位朋友
To see a friend.
您朋友的姓名是?
What's your friend's name?
- 鲁迪・库兰德 - 他住哪
Rudy Kurlander.       Where does he live?
福伊尔・德斯...福伊尔...
Foyer Des... Foyer...
- 我能看看吗 - 当然可以
Can I see that?        Yeah, of course.
- 福伊尔・德斯先驱者养老院? - 是的
Foyer Des Pionniers Nursing Home?        Yeah.
您将入住安大略省赫斯特的皇后汽车旅馆?
And you'll be staying at the Queen's Motel in Hearst, Ontario?
没错
That's right.
您将在加拿大停留多久
How long will you be in Canada?
大概两晚吧
Two nights. Maybe.
护照
Passport?
先生 您的护照过期了
Sir, your passport's expired.
- 过期了? - 对
It is?        Yeah.
您有驾照吗
Do you have a driver's license?
噢 当然有
Oh, of course.
稍等
Hang on a second.
好了 您可以走了
Alright, you're good to go.
不过请您将护照延期
But, sir, renew your passport.
我都这个岁数了 用不着了
I didn't think it was necessary at my age.
祝您与朋友相聚愉快
Have fun with your friend.
谢谢
Thank you.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
需要什么帮助吗 先生
How can I help you, sir?
鲁迪・库兰德在哪个房间
Rudy Kurlander. Which room is he in?
库兰德?
Kurlander?
对 库兰德 他在238房
Yes, Kurlander. He's in room 238.
沿着这条走廊走 坐电梯
Just go down this hallway and take the elevators.
出电梯后 左转 再右转
When you exit the elevator, make a left, then you take a right.
238号房就在你的左手边
238 will be on your left.
明白了吗
Did you get that?
我直接带您去您朋友的房间吧
Why don't I just show you where your friend's room is?
谢谢
Thank you.
你是鲁迪・库兰德吗
Are you Rudy Kurlander?
鲁迪・库兰德?
Rudy Kurlander?
我是
Here.
- 你是鲁迪・库兰德? - 是的
Are you Rudy Kurlander?        Yeah.
你是德国人吗
Are you German?
是的
Yes.
你以前在奥斯维辛集中营吗
Were you at Auschwitz?
是的
Yes.
我去过奥斯维辛集中营
I was at Auschwitz.
我全家人都在
My whole family was
奥斯维辛集中营
murdered
被杀了
at Auschwitz.
我感到很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你很...很抱歉?
You're... you're sorry?
没错
Yeah.
你的所作所为不是道个歉就足够的
What you did is something you cannot apologize for.
我发过誓我会杀死
I swore I would kill the man responsible
杀害我全家性命的那个人
for the death of my family.
你是犹太人?
You're Jewish?
我是同性恋
Homosexual.
应该是我道歉才对
It is I who am sorry.
对不起 真的很抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry!
莫什科夫斯基
Moszkowski.
你知道莫什科夫斯基?
You know Moszkowski?
我以前的钢琴老师曾说
My old piano teacher used to say
三位最伟大的作曲家分别是
that the three greatest composers
门德尔松 梅耶贝尔
were Mendelssohn, Meyerbeer
以及莫什科夫斯基
and Moszkowski.
- 你现在还弹吗 - 噢...
Do you still play?        Oh...
不
No.
不 我不知道 我不确定
No, I don't know, I'm not sure!
那么...
Well...
为什么不试试呢
Why don't you give it a try?
噢... 好吧...
Oh... Well...
门德尔松
Mendelssohn.
大概吧
Maybe.
你好 先生 欢迎来到博伊西
Hello, sir. Welcome to Boise.
您预定过了吗
Do you have a reservation?
我这边有记录您早上8点需要出租车服务
I have a note that you need a taxi pickup at 8:00 am.
我们将于6点起供应免费早餐
So, we have our complimentary breakfast which starts at 6:00 a.m.
如果您径直穿过左手边的大厅...
And if you just head through the lobby to your left...
让我来帮助您 好吗
Here, let me help you, okay?
有件事 我忘了带衣服了
There is one thing. I forgot to pack more clothes.
- 换洗的衣服 - 噢
Extra clothes.        Oh!
这个完全不是问题
We can definitely help you out with that.
每整点都有一趟公共汽车从我们这里发往市中心
So, there's a downtown shuttle that leaves every hour on the hour
这趟车会将您送到北密尔沃基路的商场
and it's going to drop you right off at the mall on North Milwaukee street.
您可以在那买到您需要的所有东西
You should be able to get everything you need there...
先生 你需要我帮您预订吗
Sir, would you like me to do that?
先生 您还好吗
Sir, are you okay?
您现在想去您的房间了吗 好嘞
Would you like to head up to your room now? Okay.
- 您需要我帮你找什么吗 - 噢 是的
Can I help you find anything?        Oh, yes.
我想买一件新衬衫
I want to buy a new shirt.
我们有很多短袖系扣衬衫
We have a great deal on short-sleeve button downs.
- 是吗 - 您要看看吗
Yeah?        Can I show you?
- 劳驾 - 不客气
Thank you.        Yeah.
季末的时候最划算了
You can always find the best deals at the end of the season.
好的
Oh, right.
抱歉 先生 您触响了警报
Excuse me, sir. You set off the alarm.
我得检查一下您的包
I'm gonna have to check your bag.
噢 我看起来像个贼吗
Oh. Do I look like a thief?
噢 跟这没关系 先生 您触响了警报
Oh, it doesn't matter, sir, you set off the alarm.
不管怎样我都得检查一下您的包
I've got to check your bag no matter what, so...
这是收据
There's the receipt.
噢 问题在这儿
Oh, there's your problem right there.
他们忘记把安全标签取下了
They left the security tag on.
我还得检查一下您另外一个包 先生
I'll have to check your other bag too, sir.
这是一把格洛克吗
Is that a Glock?
是啊
Yeah.
让我想起了我第一把枪
Reminds me of my first gun.
祝您今天过得愉快 先生
You have a good day, sir.
- 给您 非常感谢 - 谢谢 谢谢
There you go. Thanks very much.        Thank you. Thank you...
您要续杯吗
Would you like a refill?
- 好的 谢谢 - 不客气
Yes. Thank you.        You're very welcome.
你能告诉我从这儿到布鲁诺有多远吗
Could you tell me how far is Bruneau is from here?
我从没去过布鲁诺 不过那是在奥怀希郡
I've never actually been to Bruneau, but it's in Owyhee County,
所以 我觉得大概是三四十分钟的路程吧
so, I'd say that should probably take you about 30, 40 minutes or so.
- 噢 - 我听说那儿的乡下很漂亮
Oh.        I heard it's beautiful country down there.
我从没去过但是我朋友...
I never get to go but my friends...
- 噢 - 啊
Oh!        Ah.
噢 我很抱歉
Oh, I'm so sorry!
- 我把咖啡撒到你的信上了 - 噢 天啊
I got coffee on your letter.        Oh, God.
住手 你把我的信毁了
No, you're ruining my letter!
- 不要 不要 不要 - 我很抱歉
No, no, no!        I'm sorry.
这封信很重要 住手 住手 住手
This letter is very important! Stop! Stop! Stop!
除了我
"Besides me,
你是唯一一个
"you are the only person
仍然能认出
"who can still recognize
那人长相的人
"the face of the man
他杀害了我们的家人
"who murdered our families."
- 没人在家吗 - 没有
Nobody's home?        No.
您想让我把您送到其他地方吗
You want me to take you somewhere else?
- 不不不 我再等等 - 给您
No, no, no. I will wait.        Here.
您什么时候需要我回来接您就给我打个电话
Give me a call whenever you want me to come back and get you.
我该付你多少钱
What do I owe you?
噢 您已经付过钱了 记得吗
Oh, you already paid me, remember?
如果你需要乘车给我打个电话就行
Just call me if you need a ride later.
早安
Morning.
你也早安 小可爱
Morning to you too, sweetie.
没错...
Yeah...
该吃晚饭了 劳森鲍姆先生
Dinner time, Mr. Rosenbaum.
给我带点吃的来 可以吗
Bring me back some food, yeah?
您确定吗 您已经在房间里待了一整天了
Are you sure? You haven't been outside the apartment all day.
- 我确定 - 好吧
Yes.        Okay.
我能帮您什么吗
Can I help you with something?
我来找鲁迪・库兰德
I'm looking for Rudy Kurlander.
呃 您来对地方了 但是...
Well, you came to the right place but, uh...
我的爸爸3个月前去世了
My old man passed away about three months ago.
噢 我不知道这个 我很遗憾
Oh, I didn't know this. I am so sorry.
您在这儿等了多久了
How long have you been waiting here?
一整天
All day.
您要喝点什么吗
You want a drink?
那好极了
A drink would be nice.
进来吧
Come on in.
我自己也来点
I could use another drink myself.
- 谢谢你 - 要啤酒还是水
Thank you.        Beer or a water?
水就可以了 谢谢你
Just water, please.
哦 伊娃 乖 别叫了
Oh, Eva. Good girl. Good girl.
听着 我有点怕狗
Listen, I am a little scared of dogs.
伊娃不会咬人的 进来吧
Eva's all bark and no bite.Come on in.
我相信你 但我还是蛮害怕的
But I'm sure that's true but I'm... I'm quite scared.
哦 我把它带走 没问题的
Oh, I'll put her away for you. Okay.
我们走 好样的
Here we go. Good girl.
别叫了 伊娃
Quiet, girl. Eva!
伊娃 嘘 安静
Eva, shush, quiet.
安静 别叫了 伊娃 嘘
Girl, quiet. Calm down, Eva. Shush.
伊娃 嘘 嘘
Eva, shush. Shush.
伊娃 安静下来 安静
Eva, calm down now. Calm down.
别叫了
Quiet!
那是我儿子的毕业照
That's my, um, kid's graduation.
我父亲一直很喜欢那张照片
Dad always loved that photo.
- 我去...拿水给你 - 好的
- I'm gonna get... grab your water for you. - Yeah.
这张照片什么时候拍的  你父亲看起来很年轻
When was that taken? Your father looks so young.
那是 额 1997拍的
That was, uh, in 1997.
- 哦 - 对啊 老当益壮 不是吗
- Oh. - Yeah. Dad aged well, didn't he?
1997 1997.
他一直说他是库兰德家族基因最好的
He always said that he was one of the Kurlanders with good genes.
给你
Here you go.
哦 你比伊娃还渴
Oh, you were thirstier than Eva.
- 还要吗 - 好的 谢谢你
- Another one? - Oh, please.
然后就不会再麻烦你了
And then I won't bother you again.
不 不会的 完全不麻烦
Oh, no, no. It's no bother at all.
你要待多久都可以
Stay as long as you like.
自从...我父亲去世了 一个人住在这里很孤单
Ever since, uh... since Dad died, it's been pretty lonely out here.
你知道吗 我就一直在附近巡逻
You know, I'm just driving around
除了听听广播 偶尔被调派 没别的事了
doing my rounds, with nothing but the radio and the occasional dispatch.
回家时有人能跟我说说话真好
It's good to have someone to talk to when I come home.
伊娃很棒 但她毕竟不能跟我聊天
Eva's great and all，but not much for conversation.
- 你要的水 - 你没结婚?
- Here's your water. - You're not married?
不 不是的 请坐 我结过婚...两次
No, no. Have a seat. I was, you know, twice.
第一个老婆 带走了我的房子
The first one, uh, took my house,
第二个老婆 在采石场收购
the second one left before...
这套房子之前离开了
...the quarry takes this one.
那是...哇 七年前的事了
That was...Ooh, hell, seven years already.
我不介意再找一个
I wouldn't mind getting another one,
但布鲁诺不是最适合单身的人的地方
but Bruneau ain't exactly the best singles scene
而我 也不是黄金单身汉
and, well, I ain't exactly the best single.
你爸爸跟你谈起过德国吗
Did your father ever talk to you about Germany?
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
他从来没停止过讨论德国
He never stopped talking about Germany.
他有没有跟你说过关于二战的事?
Did he ever speak to you about the war?
当然
Of course.
你知道他是个收集狂吧?
You know he was a collector, right?
啊
Ah.
我有一堆他的东西 你想看看吗
I got a bunch of his stuff. You wanna go take a look?
好啊
Yeah.
小心台阶 就在这里
Watch your step. Just come down here.
伊娃 安静 伊娃 嘘
Eva, quiet! Eva, shh.
嘿 听着 额 这里有点乱
Hey, listen, uh, it's kind of a mess in here.
我得把箱子挪开 然后
Let me just move some boxes and I'll...
我带你去另一个房间
I'll let you in the other room.
这边
Here we go.
从这里 好的 来吧 哦
There we go. There. Come on. Oh!
进来吧
Come on in.
那是 额 那是我爸爸的骄傲和快乐
That was, uh...that was Dad's pride and joy.
那个卖给我们的人发誓1938年11月19日这面旗帜在柏林飞舞
The dealer he bought it from swore it was flying in Berlin on November 19, 1938.
水晶之夜
Kristallnacht.
对啊 水晶之夜
Kristallnacht... Yeah.
父亲曾经说 这面旗帜
Dad used to say that that flag, um,
见证了历史的开端
witnessed the beginning of history.
你知道吗
You know?
- 箱子里有什么? - 额 就是
- What is in these boxes?  - Uh, just...
一些父亲得到的其他奖赏 你知道
a bunch more of Dad's prize pieces. You know?
我已经卖掉了大部分的收藏
I already sold most of the collection
但是 这些是跟他有感情的
but, uh, these are the things he was sentimental about.
连我也还没办法卖了它们 你知道吗
Just haven't been able to let myself get rid of 'em, you know?
你想到处看看吗
You wanna look around?
- 感谢 - 没关系
- Thank you. - Yeah.
对 这是初刊本
Yeah, that was a first printing.
有个人想用6000美元跟我买 但我就是没办法...卖掉它
A guy offered me six grand for it but I just... just couldn't part with it.
我猜我跟我父亲一样感情用事 对吧
I guess I'm just as sentimental as my old man, huh?
你可以随便在周围看看...任何东西都可以
You're welcome to look around at... at anything you like.
我去帮伊娃准备它的晚餐
I'm just gonna give Eva her dinner.
安静 嘘
Quiet! Shh!
无价之宝 对吧
Priceless, right?
对啊
Yeah.
我想我不应该把它像那样塞在箱子里面
I guess I shouldn't leave it stuffed in a box like that.
你想要再喝点什么吗
You want another drink?
好的 那会很好
Yes. That would be good.
再来一杯水 还是烈一点的东西
More water,or something a little stronger?
烈一点的好了
Maybe something a little stronger.
好的
All right.
现在你知道我在说什么了
Now you're speaking my language.
是啊...
Yeah...
敬我父亲
To Dad.
你知道吗 我爸他...
You know, my dad was, uh...
我爸那天晚上在那
My dad was there that night.
- 哪个晚上 - 额 水晶...
- What night was that? - Um, Kristal...
- 水晶之夜 - 对 水晶之夜
- Kristallnacht. - Yeah. Kristallnacht.
对 他说他带了一个铁锤
Yeah, he said he had a hammer
他打碎了一些珠宝店的窗户
and he broke a bunch of jewelry store windows.
- 他跟你说过这件事吗 - 没有
- He ever tell you that story? - No.
没有?
No?
我真希望你在他还活着的时候来这里
I so wish you were here when he was still alive.
你知道 每过一段时间 有一些他的朋友会过来
You know, every once in a while, some of his buddies would come by
他们就会坐在这里 说一些故事 喝喝酒 你知道吗
and they'd just sit around, tell stories, drink, you know?
他很喜欢讲一些以前的事
He loved to talk about the old days.
你还好吗 你流了很多汗
You okay? You're sweating there.
- 哦 我有点热 - 把你的外套脱了吧
- Oh, I feel a little hot. Yes. - Well, take your jacket off.
来吧
Come here. Mmm.
对 把你的外套脱了 然后 我只是想要告诉你
Yeah, take your jacket off and, hey, I just want to tell you something.
- 我求之不得你能... - 哦
- You are more than welcome... - Oh.
...在这里住一晚 如果你不介意睡在我父亲的旧床上
...to spend the night if you like, if you don't mind sleeping in dad's old bed.
- 你人真好 不必了 谢谢你 - 不 不
- You're very kind. No, thank you.  - No, no.
- 好吧 反正我的提议随时有效 - 哦 谢谢你
- Well, all right, the offer's on the table. - Oh, thank you.
父亲的朋友就是我的朋友
Any friend of Dad's is a friend of mine.
你怎么认识他的 你曾经跟他一起服役?
How'd you know him? Did you serve with my dad?
- 不是 - 好吧 那你怎么认识他的
- No. - Well, how did you know him then?
我在奥斯维辛认识他的
I knew him from Auschwitz.
奥斯维辛?
Auschwitz?
我父亲很希望他能在奥斯维辛服役
My dad wished he served at Auschwitz.
你是说你父亲没去过奥斯维辛?
You mean your father was not at Auschwitz?
你在说什么...
What are you...
你是认真的吗 我父亲是军队的厨师
Are you serious? My dad was a cook in the army.
他不是集中营领袖? He was not a Blockführer?
我都不知道那是什么 不是 我父亲在战争开始的时候才10岁
I don't even know what that is. No, my dad was 10 when the war started.
德国人让他做的最多的事就是 你知道
Most that the Germans let him do was, you know,
打破一些窗户 煮一些维也纳炸牛排 你知道吗
break a bunch of windows and cook some Wiener Schnitzel, you know?
很抱歉打扰你了
I am sorry to have bothered you.
- 我找错人了 - 不 没事的 哇 哇塞
- I have the wrong Rudy Kurlander. - No, no, no. Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
等一下 你以前在奥斯维辛?
Wait a minute, you were at Auschwitz?
- 嗯 - 没有一个我爸的朋友在那里服役
- Oh. - None of my dad's buddies served at a camp.
我必须离开了 我已经打扰你很久了
I must leave you now. I have bothered you enough.
打扰我? 不 没有 请留下来
Bothered me? No, no, no. Please stay.
请留下来 分享一些故事吧
Please stay. Share some stories.
我再去拿一瓶酒 我们就...
I'll grab another bottle. We'll just...
那是什么
What's that?
What is that?
那个他妈的是什么
What the fuck is that?
额...对不起 我...
Well... I'm sorry. I...
我 额...
I, uh...
那个他妈的是什么
What the fuck is that?
你是犹太人?
Are you a Jew?
是的
Yeah.
你是一个犹太人?
You're a Jew?
现在他妈是怎么回事
What the fuck's going on here?
对不起 我...
I'm sorry, I...
干你娘 给我坐下
Sit the fuck down.
拜托你 让我走吧
Please, let me go.
你他妈在我家干吗
What the fuck are you doing in my house?
我搞错了 你父亲不是我要找的人
I made a mistake. Your father is the wrong man.
我父亲?
My father?
你说你是我父亲的朋友
You said you were a friend of my dad.
你骗我
You lied to me.
- 我没有说谎 我没有说谎 - 干你娘鸡掰
- I did not lie. I did not lie! - Jesus fucking Christ.
你说你是我父亲的朋友 你到我家里
You said you were a friend of my dad, you come into my house
还他妈的喝我的威士忌
and you drink my fucking whiskey,
而你他妈是一个肮脏的犹太人
and you're a dirty fucking Jew.
伊娃 闭上你的狗嘴
Eva, shut the fuck up!
别吼了 求你了 别再吼了 我走
Stop yelling! Please, stop yelling! I will go.
你给我坐下
Sit the fuck down!
你他妈现在立刻回答我的问题
You gotta answer some questions right fucking now!
操你妈的 你刚刚是尿在了我的沙发上吗
Holy shit! Did you just piss on my couch?
- 对不起 我很抱歉 - 操你妈
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. - What the fuck?
别再叫了
Stop yelling!
伊娃 你他妈闭嘴
Eva, shut the fuck up!
你是在命令我吗 犹太人
Are you giving me a fucking order, Jew?
伊娃 我让你闭嘴 你知道...
Eva, I said, "Shut the fuck up!" You know...
你知道如果我父亲知道他妈有一个犹太人在他家他会说什么吗
you know what my dad would say if he knew a fucking Jew was in his house, huh?
他会说 "希特勒他妈的万岁"
He would say, "Heil fucking Hitler."
没错 那就是他会说的
That's what he'd say. Yeah.
希特勒他妈的万岁! 希特勒万岁! 希特勒万岁!
Heil fucking Hitler! Heil Hitler! Heil Hitler!
希特勒万岁! 希特勒万岁 你他妈的犹太人!
Heil Hitler! Heil Hitler, you fucking Jew!
伊娃 该死的 给我安静
Eva, goddamn it, shut the fuck up!
闭嘴 你有什么问题啊
Shut up! What's your problem?
哈? 闭嘴
Huh? Shut up!
停下 伊娃 安静
Stop it! Eva, quiet!
伊娃
Eva!
该死 闭嘴 闭嘴 操你妈 安静
Damn it, shut up! Shut up, damn it! Quiet!
伊娃 冷静下来
Eva, settle down.
你他妈想要去见见活生生的犹太人吗
You want to meet a real life fucking Jew?
哈 是吗
Huh? Huh?
哈 去抓他吧
Huh? Go get him.
啊!
Ah!
我操你...
What the...
你这该死的犹太人
You fucking kike!
我操...
You fucking...
哦...
Oh...
这是约翰・库兰德
You've reached John Kurlander.
请留言吧 如果有急事 打我的手机
Leave me a message. Or if it's an emergency, call my cell phone.
露丝?
Ruth?
约翰 你在哪 你已经晚了半个小时了
Where you at, John? You're a half hour late
我不能整个早上都帮你掩护
and I can't cover your ass all morning.
- 我发誓 你最好是出车祸了... - 你在说什么
- I swear, you best be having car trouble... - What are you saying?
我的天啊
My God.
哦...
Oh...
你好
Hello.
- 马克思 我是泽夫 - 你去哪了
- Max, it's Zev. - Where have you been?
我杀了一个人
I killed a man.
额...
Uh...
现在是最难的部分了 你必须报警
Now is the hardest part. You must call the police.
- 你必须... - 不 不是的
- You must... - No, no!
他不是我们要找的人
He was not the man we are looking for.
- 那是谁 - 一个年轻很多的男人
- Who was he? - It was a much younger man.
我 额... 在一个箱子上看到了他的名字
I, uh... I saw his name on a box.
他叫做约翰・库兰德
It was John Kurlander.
他是一个纳粹
He is a Nazi.
- 你怎么知道的 - 有很多纳粹的东西
- How do you know this? - There were many Nazi things
- 在房间里 有很多东西 - 哦
- in the house. Many things. - Oh.
这不是我们的初衷
This is not what we set out to do.
泽夫
Zev.
你还想继续吗
Do you want to continue?
我想 我必须完成
Yes, I must finish.
我必须
I must.
毕竟 那是杀了我们全家的人
After all, this is the man who killed our families.
露丝?
Ruth?
露丝!
Ruth!
喂
Hello.
我是
Yes.
哦 我的天啊 谢谢你 太感谢你了
Oh, my God. Thank you. Thank you so much.
他还好吗
Is he okay?
不 他有痴呆
No, he has dementia. Mm-hmm.
不好意思 额
I'm sorry. Uh...
你是从哪里打来的? 我马上过去
Where are you calling from? I can be there right away.
里诺纪念医院?
Reno Memorial Hospital?
- 里诺 内华达州? - 里诺?
- Reno, Nevada? - Reno?
我可以跟我父亲讲话吗
Is it possible that I could speak with my father?
好的 谢谢 非常感谢你
Yeah, thank you. Thank you very much.
伙计们 我要打喷嚏了
Guys, I gotta sneeze.
喂
Hello.
哦 你好啊 查尔斯
Oh, hello, Charles.
是啊 哦 我很好 别担心
Yeah. Yeah, no, I'm fine. I'm fine.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我叫医生别去打扰你
I told the doctors not to bother you.
哈
Huh?
请你别担心我了
Please, don't you worry about me.
哦 不 不用的 你别来医院
No. No. No. Don't you come to the hospital.
你母亲会来接我的
Your mother will pick me up.
你跟她一起来?
Maybe you come with her, huh?
对啊 我很好 没事的 嗯 好的 再见
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Goodbye. Goodbye.
你喜欢卡通?
Do you like cartoons?
我喜欢迪士尼频道的
I like Disney Channel.
- 米老鼠吗 - 不是 我喜欢飞哥与小佛
- Mickey Mouse? - No. I like Phineas and Ferb.
哦
Oh.
我没听说过他们
I never heard of them.
莫利 我马上回来
I'll be right back, Molly.
你快做你的功课吧
You finish your homework please.
- 你叫莫利? - 莫利・伊丽莎白
- Your name is Molly? - Molly Elizabeth.
你喜欢糖果吗 莫利・伊丽莎白
Do you like sweets, Molly Elizabeth?
好的 额
Well, uh...
我想我的大衣口袋里有一些硬糖
I think there are some caramels in my coat pocket.
我一直为我的孙子们准备一些在那里
I always keep some there for my grandchildren.
啊
Ah.
我找不到
I can't find any.
好吧 我妻子来的时候会带一些的
Well, my wife will bring some when she comes.
- 你是泽夫吗 - 是的
- Are you Zev? - Yes.
我能看你的信吗
Can I open your letter?
可以啊
Uh-huh.
- 哇 你真有钱 - 什么?
- Whoa, you're rich! - What?
谁是马克思
Who's Max?
马克思?
Max?
我不清楚
I'm not sure.
等等 要不然你把信读给我听吧
Wait. Why don't you read the letter to me out loud?
"泽夫 有些事令人难以接受 可你得知道"
"Zev, there are some difficult things you must know."
"首先 露丝已经过世了"
"Firstly, Ruth has passed away."
"她得了癌症"
"She had cancer."
"她爱你 在她最后的时刻 你陪在她身边 握着她的手"
"She loved you and you were with her, holding her hand, at the end."
"其次 你患有痴呆症"
"Secondly, you have dementia."
"最近你变得健忘了"
"Recently you have been forgetting many things."
那很正常 老年人总是爱忘事
That's normal. Old people always forget things.
是啊 是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
"我们有着相似的经历"
"You and I have a similar history."
"我们都是奥斯维辛..."
"We are both Auschwitz..."
- 奥斯维辛 奥斯维辛 - "奥斯维辛的幸存者"
Auschwitz. Auschwitz.        "Auschwitz survivors."
"看看你的左臂 你是98814号囚犯"
"Look at your left arm, you were prisoner 98814."
"战争结束时"
"When the war ended,"
"我承诺自己"
"I promised myself"
"我要找到那些应为此负责的人"
"I would find the men responsible."
"与西蒙・威森塔尔共事期间"
"Working with Simon Wiesenthal,"
"我帮忙抓获了大批前'纳兹'分子"
"I have helped to capture dozens of former Nazis"
"他们遍布世界各地"
"all around the world."
- '纳兹'是什么       - 是纳粹 纳粹
What's a Nazi?        Nazi. Nazi.
一种坏人
A bad person.
六个月前 上帝赐我好运
Six months ago, God smiled upon me
当你搬到高级社区后
when you moved to the senior housing community.
我立刻就认出了那个曾在奥斯维辛的你
I immediately recognized you from Auschwitz,
尽管你已经不记得我
although you did not remember me.
我们是那个狱区还健在的最后的幸存者
We are the last living survivors from our prison block.
除我之外 你是唯一一个
Besides me, you are the only person
还能认出杀害我们家人的凶手面孔的人
who could still recognize the face of the man who murdered our families.
西蒙・威森塔尔坚持认为
Simon Wiesenthal insisted
所有战犯都应当受到公开审判
that all war criminals be given public trials.
但是 我们不能给瓦利施这个机会
However, we cannot give Wallisch that opportunity.
尽管证据确凿
Even if there was enough proof,
他 跟我们一样 很可能会
he, like us, would probably die
在被引渡德国之前已经去世
before he could be extradited to Germany.
我们都赞同 奥托・瓦利施必须死
We have agreed that Otto Wallisch must die.
你必须杀了他
You must kill him.
"你答应等露丝去世你就去"
"You promised to go once Ruth died.
"你答应了我 你也答应了露丝"
"You promised me and you promised Ruth."
你读得很棒
You did a very good job.
谢谢
Thanks.
露丝是谁
Who's Ruth?
我的妻子
My wife.
我还以为她能带点糖果给我
I thought she was bringing me candy.
我也希望来着
I thought so, too.
对 我要去假日旅馆
Yes, I need to go to Holiday Inn Express
塔霍湖大道3961号
3961 Lake Tahoe Boulevard.
- 在湖南岸 - 对
South Lake?         Yeah.
那得一个多小时
That's over an hour away.
- 哦 那... 我带够钱了 - 上车吧
Oh, that's... I have money.        Hop in.
- 你好 泽夫? - 是的
Hello. Zev?        Yeah.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
你在哪
Where are you?
泽夫?
Zev?
塔霍
Tahoe.
你明白你该怎么做
You understand what you must do
只剩一个人了
There's only one left.
是的 我明白
Yeah, I understand...
我该怎么做
what I must do.
- 早 - 早上好
Morning.        Good morning.
我想退房
I'd like to check out, please.
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 你的手受伤了? - 哦 对 是的
You hurt your hand?        Oh, yes, yes.
- 它...还好了 还能动 - 不错
It's... Well, I can move.        Good.
好的 总共106美元20美分
Okay, that'll be $106.20.
我想搭出租的钱是够了
I think I will have enough money for the taxi.
哦 呃 我们也能用信用卡的
Oh, uh, we take credit cards, too.
是啊
Yeah.
谢谢你
Thank you.
塔霍? 他在塔霍搞什么鬼
Tahoe? What the heck is he doing in Tahoe?
不 我正在租车
No, I'm just picking up a rental now
我想我会开车过去
and I guess I'll just drive up there.
好
Yeah.
哦 听着 你能试着找到
Oh, look, can you try and find
他搭的那辆出租所属公司的名字吗
the name of the taxi company that picked him up?
谢谢你
Thank you.
需要帮忙吗
Can I help you?
鲁迪・库兰德 他在这住吗
Rudy Kurlander, he lives here?
- 是的 - 我能跟他聊聊吗
Yes.        Can I speak with him?
- 他还在睡觉 - 哦
He's still sleeping.         Oh.
好吧 我能在这等他...醒来吗
Well, could I wait for him to... wake up?
是要紧事
It's important.
什么事啊
What's this about?
呃 是私事
Well, it's private.
而且他认得我 他认得我
And he knows me, he knows me.
我很久以前就认识他了
I knew him a long time ago.
- 进来吧 - 哦 谢谢你 谢谢你
Come on in.        Oh, thank you. Thank you.
- 需要来杯咖啡吗 您叫... - 古特曼
Do you want a cup of coffee, Mr...        Guttman.
行 咖啡挺好 谢谢你
Yes, coffee would be nice. Thank you.
- 呃 黑咖啡就好 - 在客厅坐会儿
Uh, just black.        Take a seat in the living room.
我去煮咖啡
I've got a pot brewing.
那是我们家几年前重聚的时候照的
That's from our family reunion a couple years ago.
噢
Oh.
真是个大家庭
You have a big family.
我父亲总爱说他生了一支足球队
My father likes to say he fielded a soccer team.
我是老小
I'm his youngest.
你母亲有多大
How old was your mother?
她年轻多了 父亲是二婚
She was a lot younger. It was his second marriage.
- 谢谢你 - 古特曼先生 我能问您个问题么
Thank you.        Can I ask you a question, Mr. Guttman?
您的事跟奥斯维辛有关么
Does you being here have to do with Auschwitz?
是的
Yes.
我父亲可不愿谈论那事
My father's not gonna want to talk about that.
哦
Oh.
我理解
I understand.
您愿意跟我们共进早餐吗 古特曼先生
Would you like to join us for breakfast, Mr. Guttman?
我做了些烤苹果饼
I'm making baked apple pancakes.
我不太饿 真是感谢你
I'm not very hungry. Thank you very much.
我不会打扰你太久的
I won't bother you for long.
你确定? 这可是家传秘制
Are you sure? It's an old family recipe.
嗯 是的 我确定 可还是谢谢你
Mmm. Yes, I am sure, but thank you just the same.
您等我下 我去告诉父亲您来了
If you'd excuse me, I am just going to run up and tell Dad you're here.
好 好的
Yeah, yeah.
呃 你是谁
Uh, who are you?
哦 我是泽夫
Oh, I am Zev.
- 嗨 泽夫 - 英格
Hi, Zev.       Inge
那是谁
Who is that?
那是你外公的老朋友
Well, it's an old friend of your grandfather.
你喜欢瓦格纳?
You like Wagner?
是啊 我一直都喜爱瓦格纳
Yes. I have always loved Wagner.
我女儿说来了个我认识的奥斯维辛人
My daughter said someone I knew from Auschwitz was here.
但作为一个幸存者不应该喜欢瓦格纳的 不是吗 (瓦格纳 德国作曲家 种族主义者 反犹太主义者)
But a survivor should not like Wagner, no?
音乐又不可恨
You can't hate music.
我 呃 没能在那些照片中认出你
I, uh, didn't recognize your face in those pictures.
但是...
But...
你的声音...
Your voice...
没变
has not changed.
我知道有一天你会来找我
I knew you would come to find me one day.
外公 泽夫是你朋友吗
Zev's your friend, Poppy?
英格 请你回厨房去
Inge, please go back into the kitchen.
我得跟我朋友探讨些事
My friend and I need to discuss some things.
我没忘记你
I have not forgotten you.
来吧...我们到外面去
Please... let us go outside.
我不想让我的家人听见...我们要说的事
I do not want my family to hear...what we have to say.
已经有很久...
It has been a long time...
没人认出从前的我了
since anyone knew who I was.
我甚至记不清有多久
I cannot even remember when.
这些年来 人们盯着我看
Over the years people have looked at me
我就以为他们认出我了 其实他们从来没有
and I think they know, but they never do.
或许他们只是太害怕 所以什么都不敢说
Or maybe they were just too scared to say anything.
有时候 我会到这来 说出自己的名字
Sometimes, I come out here and speak my name.
我自言自语
I talk to myself.
重新回忆起以前的那个我
I remind myself of who I was.
这是唯一一种让我知道自己存在过的方式
It is the only way to know I existed...
在我变成现在这个人之前的那个自我
before I became who I am now.
好吧 靠谎言过活算什么人生
Well, living a lie is not a life.
我一直都知道你会找到我
I always knew you would find me.
已经过了太久
It has been too long.
现在我们都是老人了
We are old men now.
把你的手拿开 奥托
Take your hands off of me, Otto.
什么
Excuse me?
我说 "把你的手拿开"
I said, "Take your hands off of me."
你叫我奥托?
You called me Otto.
我想你弄糊涂了
I think you're confused.
没有 你的名字叫奥托・瓦利施
No, your name is Otto Wallisch.
你是奥斯维辛的一个狱长 You were a Blockführer at Auschwitz.
你杀了我的家人
And you killed my family.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
你自欺欺人这么久
You've lived a lie for so long
你自己都信以为真了
you've convinced yourself it is true.
我...
I...
我不明白
I do not understand.
那我来帮你
Let me help you...
弄明白
understand.
感觉像我们开了家旅馆
It's like we're running a hotel.
去告诉外公早饭好了
Go tell Pop-Pop breakfast is ready.
- 是谁啊 - 我叫查尔斯・古特曼
Who is it?        My name's Charles Guttman.
我想我父亲在这
I think my father's here.
嗨 真抱歉打扰您
Hi, I'm so sorry to bother you,
可是我听说不久前有辆出租车载我爸爸到这
but I was told that a taxi dropped my dad off here a little while ago.
是啊 他跟我父亲在外面
Yeah, he's outside with my father.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
他已经失踪一周了
He's been missing for a week.
失踪?
Missing?
- 难以置信 跟我来 - 谢谢
I had no idea. Come on.        Thank you.
- 爸? - 哦 上帝啊
Dad?        Oh, my God.
- 妈妈 - 请别紧张
Mommy?        Please do not be frightened.
别害怕
Don't be scared.
爸 你为什么不 呃 把枪放低些
Dad, why don't you, uh, lower the gun?
- 查尔斯? - 啊
Charles?        Yeah.
- 你在这干嘛 - 呃...
What are you doing here?       Uh...
爸 把枪放下
Dad, put the gun down.
- 把枪放下 爸 - 不 不
Put down the gun, Dad.        No. No.
除非他说出真相
Not until he tells the truth.
为什么你要这样做
Why are you doing this?
告诉她们你是谁
Tell them who you are.
请你别发疯了
Please, stop this madness.
告诉她们你做了什么
Tell them what you did.
- 放过她们 拜托了 - 说英语
Leave them alone, please.        English!
我求你了
I beg you.
我要让她们听懂你说的
I want them to understand what you're saying.
爸爸 他在说什么啊
Dad, what is he talking about?
别听他的 他疯了
Do not listen to him. He is crazy!
是吗
Ach so?
你的选择很简单
You have a very easy choice.
你可以说出真相让她活下来
You can tell the truth and she lives,
你也可以撒谎 然后看着她倒下
or you can lie and watch her die.
给你三秒钟
You have three seconds.
- 一 - 拜托 别这样
One.        Please stop.
- 二 - 求你了 朝我开枪吧
Two.        Please, just shoot me.
- 爸 停下 - 三
Dad, stop it!        Three.
好吧 好吧
Okay. Okay.
好吧
Okay.
在战争期间
During the war,
我不是囚犯
I was not a prisoner.
大点声
Louder.
- 在战争期间我不是囚犯 - 再大点!
During the war I was not a prisoner.        Louder!
在战争期间我不是囚犯!
During the war I was not a prisoner!
我是个纳粹
I was a Nazi.
我是个党卫军
I was SS.
我是奥斯维辛集中营的一个狱长 I was a Blockführer at Auschwitz.
你杀过人吗
Did you kill people?
是的
Yes.
- 爷爷 你杀过人? - 你杀了多少人
You killed people, Poppy?        How many people did you kill?
我不清楚
I don't know.
很多人
Many.
现在告诉她们你的真名
And now tell them your real name.
我的名字叫...
My name is...
库尼伯特・斯德姆
Kunibert Sturm.
不对
No.
你的名字叫瓦利施!
Your name is Wallisch!
不 就是库尼伯特・斯德姆
No, it's Kunibert Sturm.
你叫奥托・瓦利施!
You are Otto Wallisch!
不
No.
是你 你叫奥托・瓦利施
You! You are Otto Wallisch!
你在撒谎
You're lying.
没有
No.
这是70年来我第一次说真话
It's the first time I haven't lied in 70 years.
你才是奥托・瓦利施
You are Otto Wallisch.
我是库尼伯特・斯德姆 我们都是奥斯维辛的狱长
I am Kunibert Sturm. We were both Blockführers.
不...
No...
我是个囚犯
I was a prisoner.
看看你的胳膊
Look at your arm.
你是98814号 我是98813号
You are number 98814. I am 98813.
是我们互相纹的 这是我们唯一的逃生办法
We tattooed each other. It was our only way to escape.
爸?
Dad?
是真的吗
Is that true?
不 都是谎言 都是谎言
No, it's all lies. It's all lies.
这不是真的
It's not true.
谎言?
Lies?
你怎么能忘记呢
How could you forget?
你给自己取名叫泽夫 因为它是狼的意思
You took the name Zev because it means wolf.
你说我俩都是狼
You said we were wolves!
哦 我的上帝
Oh, my God.
我记得
I remember.
爸?
Dad?
爸
Dad!
现在 我们还在等待
Right now, we're still waiting
来自塔霍湖警察局的消息
to hear from the Lake Tahoe Police Department.
他们仍未向记者透露或发布官方声明
They haven't spoken to reporters or released a statement just yet.
但他们向我们保证
But they have assured us
不出一小时我们将悉数获知
that we will hear from them in some way within the hour.
居民们 如你所想的那样 十分震惊
Residents, though, are,as you can imagine, just stunned.
我同一些不愿在摄像机前发表言论的人谈了谈
I've spoken to some people who do not want to comment on camera.
其中一位告诉我...
I did speak to one, though, who told me that...
- 可怜的泽夫 - 悲剧 真正的悲剧
Poor Zev.        Tragic. Absolutely tragic.
他一定不知道他在做什么
He couldn't have known what he was doing.
他很清楚他在做什么
He knew exactly what he was doing.
什么 你是什么意思 马克斯
What? What are you talking about, Max?
他杀掉的那个人
The man he killed
叫做库尼伯特・斯德姆
was named Kunibert Sturm.
而泽夫的真名
And Zev's name
叫做奥托・瓦利施
was Otto Wallisch.
就是他们两个...
They were the men who...
杀害了我的家人
murdered my family.